Finding Aid for Ernest Hemingway Collection
Clarke Historical Library
- Ernest Hemingway Collection
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #4, Posters Not Advertising Movies, E. Hemingway, Ernest Hemingway, the Dangerous Summer, Charles Scribner’s Sons, photographed by Larry Burrows, color photograph portrait on black background, with white, red, gray and yellow lettering, 18x24 inches,undated (Folder 4)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #4, Posters Not Advertising Movies, Ernest Hemingway, Havana, Cuba, 1952, Photographed aboard the Pilar by Willis W. Sanders, color photograph portrait on boat, on white background, with brown lettering, 18”x24,1994 (Folder 4)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #4, Posters Not Advertising Movies, E. Hemingway, Coleccion Vigia, Museo Ernest Hemingway. San Francisco de Paula, La Habana, CUBA, portrait in black and white, with red and black lettering, 18x27 inches,undated (Folder 4)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #4, Posters Not Advertising Movies, Hemingway at the Kennedy, 1980, ten years after, Photograph by John Suiter, color photograph of Hemingway’s WWI wallet contents on white background with gray lettering, 19x23.5 inches,1990 (Folder 4)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #4, Posters Not Advertising Movies, Finca Vigia, Coleccion Vigia, Museo Ernest Hemingway, La Habana, Cuba, color photograph of house with green edge, and white and yellow lettering, 19.5x27.5 inches,undated (Folder 4)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #4, Posters Not Advertising Movies, E. Hemingway, Finca Vigia, Coleccion Vigia, Museo Ernest Hemingway. San Francisco de Paula, La Habana, CUBA, portrait in yellow and brown, with black and brown lettering, 19x26.5 inches,undated (Folder 4)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #4, Posters Not Advertising Movies, Sala de la vigia, Coleccion VIGIA, Museo Ernest Hemingway. La Habana, CUBA, color photograph of living room, with brown edge and yellow and white lettering, 19.5x27.5 inches,undated (Folder 4)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #4, Posters Not Advertising Movies, Cigar aficionado, 100 years of Hemingway, black and white portrait photograph with yellow and black lettering, 20x26 inches,August 1999 (Folder 4)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #4, Posters Not Advertising Movies, Hemingway, Coleccion VIGIA, Museo Ernest Hemingway. La Habana, CUBA, color photograph of glasses and paper on table, with white and yellow lettering, 20x27.5 inches,undated (Folder 4)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #4, Posters Not Advertising Movies, Ernest Hemingway (portrait by Grace Hall-Hemingway of the photograph taken by Man Ray in the 1920s), photographed by Ernest H. Mainland, 22x26 inches,1990 (Folder 4)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #5, Movie Theater Lobby Posters, in color, ‘(The) Gun runners’, Window Card, 14x22 inches,1958 (Folder 5)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #5, Movie Theater Lobby Posters, in color, ‘(The) Snows of Kilimanjaro’, in Sydney, Insert, 13x30 inches,1952 (Folder 5)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #5, Movie Theater Lobby Posters, in color, ‘Islands in the stream’, Insert, 13.5x30 inches,[1976] (Folder 5)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #5, Movie Theater Lobby Posters, in color, ‘Islands in the stream’, Insert, 14x35 inches,1976 (Folder 5)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #5, Movie Theater Lobby Posters, in color, ‘Under my skin’, Insert, 14x36 inches,undated (Folder 5)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #5, Movie Theater Lobby Posters, in color, ‘(The) Sun also rises’, Insert, 14x37 inches,1957 (Folder 5)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #5, Movie Theater Lobby Posters, in color, ‘Adventures of a young man’, Insert, 14x36 inches,1962 (Folder 5)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #5, Movie Theater Lobby Posters, in color, ‘Great white hunter’, Insert, 14x36 inches,1952 (Folder 5)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #5, Movie Theater Lobby Posters, in color, ‘(the) Gun runners’, Insert, 14x36 inches,1958 (Folder 5)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #6, Huge Posters, Posters Not Advertising Movies, Ernest Hemingway “All you have to do is write one true sentence.’, Scribner (book advertisements on the back for Hemingway books), in color, 19x35 inches,July 1999 (Folder 6)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #6, Huge Posters, Posters Not Advertising Movies, Hemingway Review: University of Idaho Press, the Ernest Hemingway Foundation Paris, France, 1923 Passport photograph of Hemingway in shades of brown, white, black, and pink, 22.5x33.5 inches,July 3-8, 1994 (Folder 6)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #6, Huge Posters, Posters Not Advertising Movies, “The Old Man and the Sea” Hemingway, Fuentes, [both on the ‘Pilar’], in color, signed C. Sandowski, #749/6000, 25x37 inches,1990 (Folder 6)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #6, Huge Posters, Posters Not Advertising Movies, Ernest Hemingway and Cojimar, Fotos by Raul Corrales, black and white photograph of two men, Hemingway and Fuentes, on a bridge, on a black background with white and gray lettering, 27x38 inches,1990 (Folder 6)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #6, Huge Posters, Posters Not Advertising Movies, New Ernest Hemingway Collection, rubber poster, black, white, brown portrait of EH with metal hangers, 51x26 inches,undated (Folder 6)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #6, Movie Posters, in color, ‘(The) Gun runners’, Half Sheet, 22x28 inches,1958 (Folder 6)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #6, Movie Posters, in color, ‘(A) Farewell to arms’, One Sheet, 27.5x39 inches,1963 (Folder 6)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #6, Movie Posters, in color, 'Great white hunter', One Sheet, 27x39 inches,[1952] (Folder 6)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #6, Movie Posters, in color, ‘(The) Killers’, in black, white, and red, One Sheet, 27x39 inches,circa 1964 (Folder 6)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #6, Movie Posters, in color, ‘Por quien doblan las campanas (For whom the bell tolls’ in Spanish), 27x39 inches,[1957] (Folder 6)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #6, Movie Posters, in color, ‘In love and war’, Heavy Stock Poster, 30x40 inches,1996 (Folder 6)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #6, Movie Posters, in color, ‘(The) Macomber affair', Heavy Stock Poster, 30x40 inches,undated (Folder 6)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #6, Movie Posters, in color, ‘Islands in the stream', One Sheet, 27x41 inches,1977 (Folder 6)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #6, Movie Posters, in color, ‘(The) Snows of Kilimanjaro', 27x39 inches,[1952] (Folder 6)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #6, Movie Posters, in color, ‘Adventures of a young man',One Sheet, 27x41 inches,1962 (Folder 6)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #6, Movie Posters, in color, ‘Milosc i wojna (‘In love and war’, in Polish), One Sheet, 27x40 inches,1996 (Folder 6)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #6, Movie Posters, in color, ‘For whom the bell tolls’, One Sheet, 27x41 inches,1957 (Folder 6)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #6, Movie Posters, in color, ‘(A) Farewell to arms’, (on canvas backing), One Sheet, 29x43 inches,1950 (Folder 6)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #6, Movie Posters, in color, ‘In love and war, (in plastic), One Sheet, 27x40 inches,1996 (Folder 6)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #6, Three Sheet Movie Posters, made in two pieces, in color, ‘Adventures of a young man’, (one 27x40 inches, one 40x52 inches),1962 (Folder 6)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #6, Three Sheet Movie Posters, made in two pieces, in color, ‘Under my skin’, (one 26x40 inches, one 42x53 inches),circa 1949 (Folder 6)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #6, Advertising banner: ‘Thomasville: Ernest Hemingway: the collection of a lifetime’, a plastic-coated canvas banner advertising a furniture collection, in white, green, black, and brown, measuring 23.5x56 inches,undated (Folder 6)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #7, Plat map of Mrs. C. E. Hemingway’s property on Walloon Lake (copy) from the John F. Kennedy Presidential Library, measuring 18x24 inches,1905 (Folder 7)
  - Oversized Folders: Folder #8, Addition # 74763: Posters Not Advertising Movies (on top): Up North with the Hemingways exhibit, Midland County Historical Society, 11x17 inches, Oct. 31-Dec. 2, 2007; Ernest Hemingway, portrait with signature, 13 x19 inches, undated; Book covers, by Charles Scribner Sons, 1929, later republished as posters by Cleonike Damianakes/ Marci Economidis and the executors of the Damianakes estate, each 23.5x33 inches, undated; 1) ‘(A) Farewell to Arms’, 1929, undated; 2) ‘The Sun Also Rises’, 1929, undated; Movie Posters (on bottom): Movie Theater, Lobby Card, ‘Adventures of a Young Man’, 14x22 inches, 1962; Movie Theater Lobby Poster, ‘(A) Farewell to Arms’, torn, 14x30 inches, undated [1932] Movie Poster, In color, `Adventures de Jeunesse’, (In French), 46x62 inches, undated [1962],2007, undated [1932], [1962] (Folder 8)